本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
总算等到了
Oh, it's happening!
总算  总算等到了
It's finally, finally happening.
看得见摸得着的身体  我总算有了
Physical form? Don't mind if I do!
刚刚发生了什么
Oh! What just happened?
妈呀  这可糟糕了
Oh! Oh, man. This is bad.
这下真的糟糕了
This is real bad.
各位  我这儿出状况了
Guys, we've got a situation.
好  都听好了  你们这些一生一世的
All right, listen up, you one-life-spanned,
三维世界的
three-dimensional,
五种感官的皮囊人偶
five-sensed skin puppets.
我在我坍缩的时空
For a trillion years, I've been trapped
被困了亿万年之久
in my own decaying dimension,
等待着新宇宙对我的召唤
waiting for a new universe to call my own.
在下比尔  不过你们要称呼我
Name's Bill, but you can call me
永恒的新上帝与主人
your new lord and master for all eternity.
现在来见见我噩梦般的朋友吧
Now meet the gang of interdimensional criminals
跨时空罪犯帮
and nightmares I call my friends.
八号球  密文怪
8 Ball, Kryptos,
这位名字说不得
The Being Whose Name Must Never Be Said.
哈  逗谁玩呢
Ah, what the heck.
这位是赞萨尔  当然还有了
It's Zanthar. Then of course,
这位是牙牙  锁眼  吓人几何怪
there's also Teeth, Keyhole, Hectorgon,
无形怪  奶嘴阿罗尼卡和这些家伙
Amorphous Shape, Aronica Pacifier and these guys.
这座小镇归我们了  弟兄们
This is our town now, boys.
看好了  不洁的三角怪物
Now see here, you unholy triangle fella.
作为市长  我严正敦促你离开本镇
As mayor, I strongly urge you to get on outta here.
对啊  一只眼睛的都是怪物
Yeah. Things with one eye are weird.
外地人都滚出去
We don't like out-of-towners.
我们看不懂什么就砸什么
We punch what we don't understand.
作为富有的资本家  我只是想表示
I would just like to say that as a rich capitalist,
对专横制度的绝对拥护
I welcome your tyrannical rule.
说不定我能当个您的
Perhaps I can be one of your, uh,
末日马夫什么的
horsemen of the apocalypse.
-爸  -亲爱的  大人在说话  小孩别插嘴
- Dad! - Not now, sweetie. The grownups are talking.
哇  这工作不错啊
Oh, wow, that's a great offer.
要不换一个
How about instead,
把你五官换换位置如何啊
I shuffle the functions of every hole in your face?
杜兰德  我亲爱的副警长杜兰德啊
Durland! My precious Deputy Durland!
现在该重新装饰一下了
It's time we do a little redecorating.
有个城堡就再好不过了
I could really use a castle of some kind.
再来点包裹着纯粹疯狂的泡泡如何啊
And how about some bubbles of pure madness?
这场聚会永不散席
This party never stops.
时间停止  万事万物不再如常
Time is dead, and meaning has no meaning.
存在上下颠倒
Existence is upside down,
我将加冕为王
and I reign supreme.
欢迎  永远来到“湮没之日”
Welcome, one and all, to Weirdmageddon.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
时间轴： WaitinZ
翻译： 战忽局副局座  溪傲季  阿拱
■
校订  后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ
怪诞小镇  第二季第十八集
Gravity Falls  S02E18  Weirdmageddon Pt 1
原来这就是世界末日
So this is how the world ends.
不是大爆炸  而是有点  脑残
Not with a bang, but with a... cuckoo.
湮没之日
Weirdmageddon.
爬开  小子
Move it, stretch!
老子逃命呢  不长眼啊
Hey, we're scampering here.
裂痕被打碎了
The rift is shattered.
比尔的世界直接挤进了我们的时空
Bill's world is spilling into ours.
每时每刻  他的法力都在变得愈发强大
Every minute, his powers grow stronger.
梅宝  裂痕一定在她的背包里碎开了
Mabel... the rift must have cracked inside her backpack.
她肯定身处危险  我要去找她
She must be in danger. I have to go find her.
梅宝  回话  梅宝
Mabel. Come in, Mabel.
梅宝
Mabel!
迪普  听我说
Dipper, listen to me.
我们会尽快找你姐姐
We can find your sister soon,
但得先阻止比尔的恶行
but first, we have to stop Bill.
如果我们能把他打回那条裂缝
If we can blast him back through the rip he came out of,
我们就有一线希望
we just might be able to stop him
在他还没把这般怪诞传播至全球前阻止他
before his weirdness spreads across the entire globe.
你觉得我们真能打败比尔吗
Are you sure defeating Bill is even possible?
不  我无法保证
No, I'm not sure.
但是作为英雄  就要在毫无希望的情况下背水一战
But being a hero means fighting back even when it seems impossible.
-你要加入我的征途吗  -直到地球末日
- Will you follow me? - To the ends of the earth.
很好  地球末日也不远了
Good, because that's where we're heading.
咱们还是进去避避风头吧
You also might want to step inside.
怪诞光波来啦
Weirdness wave!
啊  奶奶  一阵怪诞光波
Ah! Abuelita, a tidal wave of madness
刚刚掠过我们
just went over us.
苏斯  别异想天开了
Oh, Soos, such an imagination.
您变成沙发了
You turned into a chair!
你坐下来喘口气吧
Why don't you have a seat and relax?
那您  和我的朋友怎么办
What about you, and my friends?
我会好好的  你去帮别人吧
I'll be fine. You go help the others.
当天崩地裂来临
When the universe is broken,
只有一个勤杂工能修复一切
only one handyman can fix it.
朋友们  我来帮你们了
I'm coming for you, friends.
该躺下休息休息了
Time for a nap.
到此为止了  山羊
That's it, goat.
我看现在该把你请出这块地方了
It's time I threw you off this property for good!
转念一想  还是像个懦夫一样逃命吧
On second thought, I'm gonna run like a coward now.
自由  自由
Freedom, freedom!
好了  各位狱友
Okay, inmates,
是时候来看看各位的手指画了
it's time to review your finger paintings.
很好  不错
Good. Nice.
复仇
吉迪恩  就你这种觉悟
Gideon, does this look like
像是要重入社会的人吗
someone who's ready to re-enter society?
这个时代辜负了吉迪恩
Gideon's unappreciated in his time.
哎呀  鬼眼  人家都脸红了
Oh, Ghost Eyes, you're making me blush.
吉迪恩让狱中生活变得很有价值
Gideon makes prison life worth living.
吉迪恩  吉迪恩
Gideon, Gideon...
我的天啊  是比尔来了
Oh, my, Bill came through.
弟兄们  准备好搞破坏了吗
Ready to cause some havoc, boys?
这就是我的量子紊乱制造器
Ah, my quantum destabilizer.
算是我的终极宝贝武器
Been waiting a long time to use this.
开火的机会只有这一次
We're only gonna have one chance to take this shot.
稳住  稳住
Steady. Steady.
准备
And...
我活过来啦
I'm alive now.
噢  不
Oh, no!
哎哟  看来今天的热闹还不止于此
Well well well... And here I thought today couldn't get any better.
阿福叔公
Great-uncle Ford!
迪普  拿好日志
Dipper, take my journals.
听着  我还知道一种打败比尔的方法
Listen. I know of one other way to defeat Bill.
那就是
It's...
噢不  迪普  快跑  快下楼
Oh, no, Dipper, run! Get down!
我的六指老伙计
Good old Six Fingers.
我等了无尽的时光
I've been waiting an eternity
才换来与你一见的机会
to have a chat face to face.
各位  这个世界末日没有这位朋友的
Everyone, this Armageddon wouldn't be possible
鼎力相助是绝对成不了的
without help from our friend here.
给他鼓个六指掌
Give him a six-fingered hand.
这个天才还是最先帮我建造传送门的家伙呢
This brainiac is the one who built the portal in the first place.
别这么难受嘛  阿福
Don't look so sour, Fordsie.
现在加入我还不迟呢
It's not too late to join me.
有六根指头的话
With that extra finger,
加入怪物大军绝对不成问题
you'd fit right in with my freaks.
加入你们我还不如死了好
I'll die before I join you.
比尔  我对你的弱点了如指掌
I know your weakness, Bill.
真的吗  给你个谜语猜猜
Oh, yeah? And I know a riddle.
-为什么老头子要这样  -这样
- Why did the old man do this? - This?
因为老子缺痒痒挠了
Because I needed a new back scratcher.
够了
That's enough!
把叔公还给我  不然有你好看
Hand over my uncle, or else!
这下还
Now isn't this...
真有意思
interesting?
我的旧人偶回来加演节目啦
My old puppet is back for an encore.
你觉得你能阻止我
You think you can stop me?
来吧  松树  看看你有什么能耐
Go ahead, Pine Tree, show me what you got.
我
I...
如果他获得了实体形态  就一切都完了
别磨叽了  行动吧  小子
"I, um, I..." Do it, kid.
现在就干点什么来打败我啊
Do some brilliant thing that takes me down right now.
松树  你有啥能耐
What do you got, Pine Tree?
全世界都等着呢  快来啊
Everyone's waiting. Do it!
比尔
Bill!!
学到了吧  别想逞英雄  小屁孩
That's right. Don't be a hero, kid.
在我的世界  这就是英雄的下场
This is what happens to heroes in my world.
别啊  日志
No! The journals!
现在你对我没什么威胁了
Not much of a threat now, are you?
现在谁能告诉我来这儿为了什么
Now can anyone remind me why we came here?
闹个天翻地覆
To get weird!
没错  在恐惧环绕之中的贵宾派对开始啦
That's right. VIP party at the Fearamid.
还有  八号球和牙牙  赏你们一顿加餐
Oh, and 8 Ball, Teeth, you've earned a treat.
把那孩子当点心吃了吧
Have the kid for a snack.
疯子随从们  动起来
Hench maniacs, roll out!
你说呢  吃掉他还是干点别的
So you wanna eat him or something?
当然是吃掉  开动吧
Oh, definitely. Let's eat him.
今天是这场诡异的灾难性事件发生的第三天
We're day three in this strange cataclysmic event
也有人称这场灾难为“湮灭之日”
which some are calling Weirdmageddon,
或者怪诞末日
or the Odd-pocalypse.
今天的天气是黑云血雨
Weather today calls for black clouds, blood rain,
还有如阵雨般游荡的眼球蝙蝠
and frequent showers of eyeball bats
所及之处人尽石化
turning people into stone.
我是珊多拉・西梅内斯  晚餐我吃了一只老鼠
I'm Shondra Jiminez, and I ate a rat for dinner.
梅宝  是我
Mabel, it's me.
目前  我躲避了各种追捕
So far, I've eluded capture,
但是哪儿也找不到你和斯坦叔公
but I haven't been able to find you or Stan anywhere.
不知道你听不听得见
I don't know if you can hear me,
但是不管你在哪里  不管发生什么事
but wherever you are, whatever happens,
我都会找到你的
I'm going to find you.
购物中心  也许他们躲在那儿
The mall! Maybe they're hiding in there.
-不会吧  -嘿  你好
- Oh, no. - Hey. Hey, you.
我想和你谈谈
Hey, I wanna talk to you.
谈谈关于进我嘴里的事
I wanna talk to you about going inside my mouth.
你会想进去瞧瞧的
I think you wanna get in here.
喂  就是你  和你说话呢
Hey, you! Hey, I'm talkin' to you!
没必要这么大惊小怪吧
You don't have to make a big deal outta this.
你好  喂
Hello. Hello!
你为什么要无视我
Why are you just ignoring me?
这样无视别人
That's seriously rude
真的很不礼貌
to just ignore someone like that.
斯坦  梅宝
Stan! Mabel!
或许至少我能填饱肚子
Maybe at least I can get something to eat.
地球上最后的墨西哥玉米片
The last nachos on Earth.
救命  上了玉米片的当了
Help! The nachos tricked me!
迪普
Dipper?
温蒂  不会吧
Wendy? Oh, no.
你被变成某种树妖怪物了吗
You've been transformed into some sort of tree monster.
只是伪装啦
It's just camouflage.
我爸每年都会让我们几个孩子做末日特训
My dad made me and my brothers do apocalypse training
代替庆祝圣诞节
every year instead of Christmas.
这种荒唐的妄想竟能收获回报  感觉不错啊
Guess it's sort of cool their paranoia paid off.
好样的  蝙蝠肉
Nice! Bat meat.
我把你放下来吧
Let me get that for you.
温蒂  能找到你真是太好啦
Wendy, I'm so glad to find you.
我以为所有认识的人都没了
I thought everyone I knew was gone.
嘿  没事的
Hey, hey, it's okay.
现在我们两个能相依为命
We have each other now.
还有托比・迪特敏德
And Toby Determined,
我不小心把他也当成怪物了
who I accidentally mistook for a monster.
插播新闻  我的肩膀中了一箭
This just in: This arrow in my shoulder.
我们不该在外面呆太久
We shouldn't stay out in the open for too long.
给你瞧瞧我的秘密基地
Let me show you my hideout.
灾变发生的时候  我们正在墓地里
We were playing Truth Or Dare in the cemetery
玩真心话大冒险
when it happened.
那些眼球定住了内特  李  谭布丽和汤普森
The eyeballs froze Nate, Lee, Tambry and Thompson.
罗比差点儿就成功逃脱了
Robbie almost got away,
可惜他非得停下来自拍
but had to pause to take a selfie.
你怎么样
What about you?
我当时正和梅宝闹矛盾
I was in a fight with Mabel when it happened.
阿福叔公让我暑假结束之后
Uncle Ford asked me to be his apprentice
做他的徒弟
after the summer was over.
但那样就意味着我回不了家
But that would mean I wouldn't go back home.
也就是说我今后不能和梅宝一起成长
It would mean growing up without Mabel.
噢  伙计
Oh, dude.
梅宝有些接受不了
Mabel didn't take it well,
然后她跑到森林里面去了
and she ran off into the forest.
甚至没有再瞧我一眼
She couldn't even look me in the eye.
来  我们出去透透气吧
Come on, let's get some fresh air.
托比  看好大本营
Toby, you watch the camp.
别再叫我托比了
Don't call me Toby anymore.
叫我非凡之T
Call me Bodacious T.
绝不会有人那样叫你的
No one will ever call you that.
世界末日到了  天呐
End of the world. Man.
那些死亡金属专辑的封面竟然成真了
Those death metal album covers got it shockingly right.
过去我以为自己能解决一切困难
You know, I used to think I could get out of anything.
不过这一次呢  日记被毁了
But this? The journals are destroyed,
阿福叔公被抓
Ford is captured,
我到处都找不到我的家人
and I can't find my family anywhere.
比尔他自己说过
Bill said it himself.
这地方没有英雄的立足之地
There's no room for heroes out here.
我们输了
We lost.
伙计  还没完呢
Look, dude, it's not over yet.
之前你打败过比尔两次
You've beaten Bill twice before.
这次为什么不能呢
Why is this time any different?
因为以前有梅宝在
'Cause then, I had Mabel.
那你就要把梅宝找回来
Then you need to get Mabel back.
听着  这个暑假  我见识到了许多神奇的事
Look, this summer, I've seen some amazing things,
但最出色的还是你们姐弟俩
but nothing as amazing as you and your sister.
我不知道你们是傻人有傻福
I don't know if it's dumb luck,
还是阴阳相生什么的
or yin and yang or whatever,
但只要你们俩携手合作
but when you two work together,
就没有干不成的事
there's nothing you two can't accomplish.
你们只需要和好如初  团结合作
You just need to make up and team up,
拯救全宇宙
and save the universe.
但是我怎样才能找到她
But how will I ever find her?
梅宝毛衣上的流星图案
The shooting star from Mabel's sweater.
她在那里  我就知道
She's in there. I know it.
哇  这就是双胞胎之间的特殊感应吗
Whoa, is that like twin ESP?
不  我们没那么神
No, we don't have that.
但我们两个的确有些感应  我们过敏时
But we do have this thing where our allergies
症状完全一样  时间也一致
totally act up at the same time.
梅宝需要我们
Mabel needs us.
我们怎么才能躲过抓捕  到那里去呢
How are we gonna get out there without being caught?
我有个主意
I have an idea.
转转人  转转人
Spin that person, spin that person.
转转人
Spin that person.
尽情疯吧  伙计们
Go nuts, guys.
等我们狂欢够了  我就公布第二阶段的内容
When we're done partying, I unveil phase two.
开门  我们是警察
Open up. This is the police.
时间警察
Time police.
镇定一点  别喝时间果汁了
Just play it cool. Ditch the time punch.
我来和他们谈
Let me do the talking.
比尔・赛弗  你违反了时空法则
Bill Cipher, you are in violation of the rules of Spacetime,
还附在一名时间警官的身上
and possessing the body of a time officer.
我的身体宛如圣殿  你好大的胆子
My body is a temple. How dare you?
听着  赛弗
Hear this, Cipher.
啊  时光宝宝
Ugh, Time Baby.
如果你继续在这个时空制造裂口
If your rip in this dimension continues,
这里一切存在的特有结构都会毁灭
it could destroy the very fabric of existence.
投降吧  否则你就得直面我的怒火
Surrender now or face my tantrum.
不  你要发脾气了
Oh, no, a tantrum.
我该如何是好
Whatever will I do about that?
这样如何
How about this?
天呐
Aw, snap!
他杀了时光宝宝
He just killed Time Baby.
天呐  事情本来就不妙  这下全完了
Oh, man, this has gone from bad to worse.
我还是用时间闪避走为上吧
I gotta get out of Time Dodge.
老大  松树小子在我们吃他之前就跑掉了
Boss, the pine tree kid got away before we could eat him.
您担心他可能会惹什么乱子吗
Are you worried he might try to cause some trouble?
对  比如梅宝的泡泡
Yeah, trouble with Mabel's bubble?
哈哈  我并不担心
Ha! I'm not worried.
这事儿我已经派专人去处理了
I've got someone on the case.
报废的汽车市场
The abandoned auto mart.
全是免费车  用电线打着火就能开走
Free cars, ripe for the hot wiring.
我们找到接梅宝的座驾了
We have found our ride to Mabel.
不知他们这儿有没有坦克
Wonder if they have a tank.
我一直都想开坦克呢
I always wanted to drive a tank.
不敢相信这地方就这么废弃了
I can't believe this place is just abandoned.
空气清新剂
Oh, an air freshener.
我终于能让自己闻着有点人味儿了
Finally, I'll smell like a person.
偷偷地  悄悄地
Stealy, stealy. Ah!
区区一只飞镖别想放倒
Huh, it's gonna take more than one dart to keep me...
不  托尼
Oh, no. Tony!
是叫托尼吗  我总记不住他名字
Was it Tony? I can never remember his name.
瞧瞧  看来我们抓到了一对步行者
Well, well, looks like we got ourselves a pair of ground walkers.
哈哈  步行者
Ha ha, ground walkers.
连个轮子都没有
Ain't got no wheels.
听着  二手车勇士们
Listen, discount auto warriors.
我们只想去东边那个泡泡那里
We just wanna make it to that bubble out east.
我们之间无冤无仇
We have no quarrel with you.
你们这样想就不对了
Oh, but that's where you're wrong.
举起手来  好让我能看到
Hands where I can see 'em.
你们俩哪儿也不许去
Y'all fellers ain't goin' nowhere.
你们
Y'all?
俩
Fellers?
等等  吉迪恩吗
Wait. Gideon?
是治安官吉迪恩
That's Sheriff Gideon.
以比尔・赛弗之名
Under the authority of Bill Cipher,
我宣布逮捕你们
I place you two under arrest.
嗨  温蒂  我们还没正式见过吧
Hi, Wendy. Have we formally met?
瞧瞧世界末日把谁扯来了
Look who the apocalypse dragged in.
你俩现在可惹上大麻烦了
Y'all are in a 12-piece bucket of deep fried trouble now.
鬼眼  痰盂
Ghost Eyes, spittoon.
是吉迪恩的风格
It's Gideon.
而且越来越接地气了
And he's gotten folksier.
我的老朋友比尔猜到你们可能想救梅宝
My old pal Bill figured you might try to rescue Mabel,
所以他任命我为这些荒地的领主
so he appointed me master of these wastelands,
以及泡泡的监管者
and keeper of the bubble.
我的宝贝儿梅宝关在那里
My sweet, precious Mabel's trapped inside,
而唯一的钥匙就挂在我的
and I have the only key wrapped around my...
好吧  准确的说不能称之为脖子
well, I wouldn't call it a neck exactly.
就挂在我头下方的这团小肉肉上
Wrapped around this little pocket of fat under my head.
吉迪恩  你无权把她关在那里
Gideon, you have no right to keep her in there.
比尔给我解释得清楚明了
Bill explained it to me nice and simple.
上天注定她是属于我的
She was always destined to be mine,
在我的笼子里
and now that I have her in a cage,
她会学着爱上我
she'll learn to love me.
我有一生一世的时间等下去
I have an eternity to wait.
鬼眼  准备好护送我们的朋友去比尔的地牢了吗
Ghost Eyes, ready to escort our friends to Bill's dungeon?
不
No.
你不会得逞的  吉迪恩
This isn't gonna work, Gideon.
是么  为什么呢
Oh? And why's that?
因为等我打断了鬼眼的胳膊
Because after I break Ghost Eyes' arm,
从你脖子上偷了钥匙后
and steal that key from your neck,
我会把你的屁股像水晶拖鞋一样一脚甩飞
I'm gonna wear your butt on my foot like a rhinestone slipper.
你凭什么觉得自己能做到呢
And what makes you think you can do all that?
就凭我是超杀科多莱家的人
'Cause I'm a flippin' Corduroy!
鬼眼  我的随从天使
Ghost Eyes, my hench angel.
后退
Get back!
后退  否则我就把他踢飞  说到做到
Get back, or I will drop-kick him, I swear.
你们现在是插翅难逃  听见没有
You'll never get away with this, you hear me?
你猜怎么着  我们这就要飞了
Guess what? We already did.
温蒂  你是我所见过最酷的人
Wendy, you're the coolest person I know.
我知道  哥们儿  一会儿再跟我说吧
I know, dude. Tell me about it later.
快追
After them!
-你要坐儿童安全座椅吗  -要  谢谢
- You want your baby seat? - Yes, please.
不能让他们到梅宝那儿去
We are not letting them get Mabel.
二手车市场勇士们  出发
Discount Auto Mart warriors, roll out!
我们要做的就是领先吉迪恩的爪牙
Okay, all we have to do is outrace Gideon's henchmen,
打开泡泡  救出梅宝  拯救世界
unlock the bubble, save Mabel, save the world.
一个小问题  你有驾照吗
Quick question: did you ever get your driver's license?
当然没有  胳膊
Definitely not. Arm!
我不能让他们放了梅宝
I can't let 'em free Mabel.
再跟我说一遍你为什么要把女朋友关进泡泡监狱里
Remind me why you're keeping your girlfriend in a prison bubble again.
我们本是犯人  现在变成狱卒了吗
Have we, the prisoners, become the wardens?
她爱我  只是她现在还不知道罢了
She loves me. She just doesn't know it yet.
-别扯这些哲学问题了  -抱歉  我大学主修哲学
- Now quit the philosophy. - Sorry. It was my major.
那些古怪的泡泡把路封住了
Ha! Weirdness bubble blockin' the path.
太好了  我们要追上了
Ooh-wee! We got 'em now.
小心  绕开那个泡泡场
Watch it. Go around that bubble field.
没法绕开  坐稳了  我们要穿过去了
No way around. Hold on! We're goin' through.
那里面有什么
What's even in there?
不知为何，我现在很想吃虫子。
吃虫子！向南飞！归巢！
太恐怖了
That was horrible.
又来了一个  坚持住
Here comes another one, dude. Brace yourself!
温蒂  我们就要到了
Wendy, we're almost there.
只要飞跃那道悬崖
We just have to make that jump.
从没上过的驾驶课  别让我失望啊
Total lack of driver's training, don't fail me now.
近在咫尺了
So close.
梅宝  我就
Mabel... I'm...
要到了
almost there.
嗨  迪普  最近咋样
Hey, Dipper. How's it hangin'?
-苏斯  -苏斯
- Soos! - Soos?
末日勤杂工  为您效劳
Handyman of the apocalypse, at your service.
苏斯  你是怎么  你从哪儿
Soos, how'd you... where'd you...
我就像个亡命之徒一直在这里闲逛
I've been wandering the plains like a desperado,
帮帮陌生人
helping strangers.
我猜现在都有些歌颂我的民谣了
I guess there are some folk songs about me now.
让我瞧瞧你的伤势
Let me see what the damage is here.
好消息是你的胳膊没事
The good news is, your arm is okay.
坏消息呢
What's the bad news?
坏消息是  哥们儿  我们被包围了
Bad news is, we're surrounded, dudes.
我猜你们刚才差点就胜过我了
I daresay you almost had a jump on me there for a second.
但现在这里已经不是你们的重力泉了
But this ain't your Gravity Falls anymore.
在这儿  我是赢家
Out here, I win.
比尔的蝙蝠手下随时都会过来抓住你们
Bill's hench bats will be here any minute to retrieve y'all.
现在梅宝是我的了
Mabel's mine now!
是吗
Is she?
是啊  我把她关起来了
Well, yeah. I have her trapped.
所以梅宝是我的了
Ergo, Mabel is mine.
听我说  吉迪恩
Gideon, listen to me.
如果说这个暑假我学到了什么
If I've learned anything this summer,
那就是无法强迫一个人爱上你
it's that you can't force someone to love you.
你只能努力让自己成为
The best you can do is strive to be
一个值得被爱的人
someone worthy of loving.
我值得被爱
Oh, I'm worthy of lovin'.
这些囚犯爱我
These prisoners love me.
可梅宝不爱你  因为你很自私
But Mabel doesn't, because you're selfish.
不过你可以改变
But you can change.
比尔以为这个世界上没有英雄
Bill thinks there's no heroes in this world,
但如果我们齐心协力  共同反击
but if we work together and fight back,
我们就能打败他
we can defeat him.
你想成为梅宝的英雄吗
You wanna be Mabel's hero?
挺身反抗比尔  我们好救她
Stand up to Bill and let us save her.
那样简直疯了
That's crazy.
你知道那样做比尔会把我怎么样吗
You know what Bill would do to me if that happens?
-你害怕比尔  -不  我
- You scared of Bill? - No, I...
这情况有点复杂
It's a complicated situation.
扪心自问  吉迪恩
Look inside, Gideon.
如果这一切是为了梅宝
If all this is for Mabel,
那么问问自己  梅宝希望你怎么做
then ask yourself what Mabel would want you to do.
迪普  你会告诉她我做的事吗
Dipper, will you tell her what I did?
当然会
Of course.
我希望这件事上你是对的
I hope you're right about this.
伙计们  新计划
Guys, new plan.
比尔的走狗们马上就要到这里了
Bill's minions are gonna be on us in seconds.
但我不会让那个愚蠢的三角怪物
But I'm not gonna let that dumb triangle
囚禁我的人生
be the warden of me.
大家伙儿准备好来一场精彩的老派监狱斗殴了吗
Y'all ready for a good, old-fashioned prison brawl?
兄弟  我们永远支持你
We're behind you for life, brother.
和小孩儿打架没劲
Fighting children is boring.
跟混沌之神干仗才像话嘛
Fighting a chaos god sounds fun.
伙计们  我们行动吧  出发
Let's do this! Henchmen, roll out!
我还以为我得出手了呢
Whew! And I thought I was gonna have to throw down.
记住  伙计们  这泡泡监狱是比尔设计的
Okay. Remember, guys, this is a prison bubble designed by Bill.
里面什么事都可能发生  要做好心理准备
We've gotta prepare ourselves for what we find in here.
不管是什么  我们都会一起面对
Whatever it is, we'll do it together.
-为了梅宝  -为了梅宝
- For Mabel. - For Mabel.
为了梅宝
For Mabel.
未完待续...
有人想进我的嘴里吗
Anybody wanna get in my mouth?
我是个又大又饿的怪兽
I'm a big, hungry monster.
又大又饿的怪兽哦
I'm a big, hungry monster here.
如果有人愿意我会非常感激
I would really appreciate it if someone...
你  夫人  就是你
You, ma'am, you, ma'am,
你想不想进我的
how would you like to get in...
有人吗  喂
Anybod... hello!
喂  先生  先生
Hey, sir, sir.
搞错了  只是一只鸟
False alarm. It's just a bird.
没一个人
Not one person.
没有一个人进到我嘴里
Not one person has gotten in my mouth.
我也看开了  我只是
I don't care anymore. I just...
我去给我妈打个电话
I gotta call my mother.